nrkanter11@gmail.com

603-714-2234

in linkedin.com/in/nrkanter

www.nathankanter.net



ABOUT ME

When it comes to my career, I refer to myself as the tech translator. I create interactive visuals to help make a variety of subjects digestible for different clientele. I utilize these skills to work with executives to gather data-based business. Having worked in multiple industries, I have experience in the medical, entertainment, and engineering fields. In my spare time, I play bass, collect retro and modern video games, and cook new recipes.

EDUCATION

Purdue University West Lafayette, IN (2018 - 2022)

Double Major:
Data Visualization
Web Programming & Design

Nathan Kanter

Data Visualization Specialist

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Visualization Specialist - NTT Data Services (2022 - 2023)

- Client Projects utilizing scrum methodologies for an international airline and a major entertainment and production company
- Managed and trained offshore delivery resources to assist in the completion of client engagements
- Generated timelines and schedules to meet client deadlines
- Negotiated with client SVPs to create terms for project delivery
- Performed data management and configuration with client data
- Generated dashboards on ITSM processes (ServiceNow) utilizing the process mining software Celonis
- Delivered internal trainings on data visualization and design theory
- Performed in-depth data analysis to recognize patterns within a client's data to realize millions in savings

Data Research Analyst - Purdue University (2019 - 2022)

- Was the Byrd Visualization Lab's Tech lead on Lupus project
- Researched Adolescent Lupus Symptom Clusters to find possible trends and connections
- Created Tableau Dashboards and interactable python visualizations
- Became very knowledgeable in Lupus to communicate with the hospital personnel
- Made a major discovery that will significantly help adolescents with Lupus

Finance Data Analyst - Roche Diagnostics (2021)

- Worked with SQL and Alteryx for database management
- Developed Tableau Dashboard on the actuals for the VP of Finance
- Created a website to assist the finance department with internal operations
- Presented to the company CFO to help him and his team understand the complexities of their financial data

Certifications

- Celonis EMS Technical Expert
- Celonis Solution Creation Expert
- Celonis Value Realization Expert
- ServiceNow Certified System Administrator
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- Skillsoft SQL*Plus Commands